Core Java, 8th Edition

Core Java. Volume I. Fundamentals, 8th Edition
Core Java. Volume II. Advanced Features, 8th Edition

官方网站
http://horstmann.com/corejava.html

------------------------------------------------
Core Java. Volume I. Fundamentals, 8th Edition
------------------------------------------------
Author: Cay S. Horstmann, Gary Cornell
Publisher: Prentice Hall PTR
Number Of Pages: 864
Publication Date: 2007-09-11
Sales Rank: 15617
ISBN-10/ASIN: 0132354764 
ISBN-13/EAN: 9780132354769
Binding: Paperback
Manufacturer: Prentice Hall PTR
Studio: Prentice Hall PTR
Average Rating: 5 

This revised edition of the classic Core Java™, Volume I–Fundamentals, is the definitive guide to Java for serious programmers who want to put Java to work on real projects.


Fully updated for the new Java SE 6 platform, this no-nonsense tutorial and reliable reference illuminates the most important language and library features with thoroughly tested real-world examples. The example programs have been carefully crafted to be easy to understand as well as useful in practice, so you can rely on them as an outstanding starting point for your own code.
 

Volume I is designed to quickly bring you up to speed on what’s new in Java SE 6 and to help you make the transition as efficiently as possible, whether you’re upgrading from an earlier version of Java or migrating from another language. The authors concentrate on the fundamental concepts of the Java language, along with the basics of user-interface programming. You’ll find detailed, insightful coverage of

Java fundamentals
Object-oriented programming
Interfaces and inner classes
Reflection and proxies
The event listener model
GUI programming with Swing
Packaging applications
Exception handling
Logging and debugging
Generic programming
The collections framework
Concurrency
For detailed coverage of XML processing, networking, databases, internationalization, security, advanced AWT/Swing, and other advanced features, look for the forthcoming eighth edition of Core Java™, Volume II—Advanced Features (ISBN: 978-0-13-235479-0).

 
Review:

Latest edition of an old favorite updated for Java 6

This is the latest edition and eighth round of the "Core Java" series of books. When it first came out in 1996 it had no competitors, and now alternatives abound, in particular the "Head First" series for learning Java published by O'Reilly and Associates. However, this is still my recommendation both for people who are learning Java and for those who are old pros and just want to catch up on what's new in the language. There are plenty of code examples, and the explanations are very clear as in the previous editions. This series always comes in two volumes - the fundamentals volume appears first followed by an "advanced features" volume a few months later. Both are usually worthwhile due to their comprehensive coverage of the language. The following is the table of contents for the eighth edition, not yet shown on the product page at the time I am writing this: 

Chapter 1: An Introduction to Java 1 
Java As a Programming Platform 2 
The Java "White Paper" Buzzwords 2 
Java Applets and the Internet 7 
A Short History of Java 9 
Common Misconceptions about Java 11 

Chapter 2: The Java Programming Environment 15 
Installing the Java Development Kit 16 
Choosing a Development Environment 21 
Using the Command-Line Tools 22 
Using an Integrated Development Environment 25 
Running a Graphical Application 28 
Building and Running Applets 31 

Chapter 3: Fundamental Programming Structures in Java 35 
A Simple Java Program 36 
Comments 39 
Data Types 40 
Variables 44 
Operators 46 
Strings 53 
Input and Output 63 
Control Flow 71 
Big Numbers 88 
Arrays 90 

Chapter 4: Objects and Classes 105 
Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming 106 
Using Predefined Classes 111 
Defining Your Own Classes 122 
Static Fields and Methods 132 
Method Parameters 138 
Object Construction 144 
Packages 15 
The Class Path 160 
Documentation Comments 162 
Class Design Hints 167 

Chapter 5: Inheritance 171 
Classes, Superclasses, and Subclasses 172 
Object: The Cosmic Superclass 192 
Generic Array Lists 204 
Object Wrappers and Autoboxing 211 
Methods with a Variable Number of Parameters 214 
Enumeration Classes 215 
Reflection 217 
Design Hints for Inheritance 238 

Chapter 6: Interfaces and Inner Classes 241 
Interfaces 242 
Object Cloning 249 
Interfaces and Callbacks 255 
Inner Classes 258 
Proxies 275 

Chapter 7: Graphics Programming 281 
Introducing Swing 282 
Creating a Frame 285 
Positioning a Frame 288 
Displaying Information in a Component 294 
Working with 2D Shapes 299 
Using Color 307 
Using Special Fonts for Text 310 
Displaying Images 318 

Chapter 8: Event Handling 323 
Basics of Event Handling 324 
Actions 342 
Mouse Events 349 
The AWT Event Hierarchy 357 

Chapter 9: User Interface Components with Swing 361 
Swing and the Model-View-Controller Design Pattern 362 
Introduction to Layout Management 368 
Text Input 377 
Choice Components 385 
Menus 406 
Sophisticated Layout Management 424 
Dialog Boxes 452 

Chapter 10: Deploying Applications and Applets 493 
JAR Files 494 
Java Web Start 501 
Applets 516 
Storage of Application Preferences 539 

Chapter 11: Exceptions, Logging, Assertions, and Debugging 551 
Dealing with Errors 552 
Catching Exceptions 559 
Tips for Using Exceptions 568 
Using Assertions 571 
Logging 575 
Debugging Tips 591 
Using a Debugger 607 

Chapter 12: Generic Programming 613 
Why Generic Programming? 614 
Definition of a Simple Generic Class 616 
Generic Methods 618 
Bounds for Type Variables 619 
Generic Code and the Virtual Machine 621 
Restrictions and Limitations 626 
Inheritance Rules for Generic Types 630 
Wildcard Types 632 
Reflection and Generics 640 

Chapter 13: Collections 649 
Collection Interfaces 650 
Concrete Collections 658 
The Collections Framework 689 
Algorithms 700 
Legacy Collections 707 

Chapter 14: Multithreading 715 
What Are Threads? 716 
Interrupting Threads 728 
Thread States 730 
Thread Properties 733 
Synchronization 736 
Blocking Queues 764 
Thread-Safe Collections 771 
Callables and Futures 774 
Executors 778 
Synchronizers 785 
Threads and Swing 794


------------------------------------------------------
Core Java. Volume II. Advanced Features, 8th Edition
------------------------------------------------------

Author: Cay S. Horstmann, Gary Cornell
Publisher: Prentice Hall PTR 
Pages: 1056 
Publication Date: 2008-04-19 
ISBN-10/ASIN: 0132354799 
ISBN-13/EAN: 9780132354790 
Binding: Paperback

The revised edition of the classic Core Java. Volume II–Advanced Features, covers advanced user-interface programming and the enterprise features of the Java SE 6 platform. Like Volume I (which covers the core language and library features), this volume has been updated for Java SE 6 and new coverage is highlighted throughout. All sample programs have been carefully crafted to illustrate the latest programming techniques, displaying best-practices solutions to the types of real-world problems professional developers encounter.

Volume II includes new sections on the StAX API, JDBC 4, compiler API, scripting framework, splash screen and tray APIs, and many other Java SE 6 enhancements. In this book, the authors focus on the more advanced features of the Java language, including complete coverage of 

Streams and Files 
Networking 
Database programming 
XML 
JNDI and LDAP 
Internationalization 
Advanced GUI components 
Java 2D and advanced AWT 
JavaBeans 
Security 
RMI and Web services 
Collections 
Annotations 
Native methods

For thorough coverage of Java fundamentals–including interfaces and inner classes, GUI programming with Swing, exception handling, generics, collections, and concurrency–look for the eighth edition of Core Java. Volume I–Fundamentals (ISBN: 978-0-13-235476-9).